<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Worked example: Custom domain on Outcome documentation</title>
    <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Worked example: Custom domain on Outcome documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 23:38:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Define a custom code domain</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/preamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/preamble/</guid>
      <description>Firstly let&amp;rsquo;s alias the experimental Outcome namespace into something less tedious to type, declare our custom status code type, and get started on defining the custom status code domain implementation.
namespace outcome_e = OUTCOME_V2_NAMESPACE::experimental; // To define a `file_io_error` which participates in the P1028 world // of `std::error`, we must first declare, then define, a custom code // domain which extends `posix_code` (the std error coding for POSIX // failures). The following is fairly standard boilerplate for defining // a custom code domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The payload</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/value_type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/value_type/</guid>
      <description>We define the code domain&amp;rsquo;s value_type &amp;ndash; the payload to be transported by status codes using this code domain &amp;ndash; to be a POSIX errno value, an integer line number and a const char pointer.
public: // This is the value type for `file_io_error`. We add line number and source file path.  struct value_type { typename outcome_e::posix_code::value_type errcode; // from POSIX, as we inherit from _posix_code_domain  // Our additional payload  int lineno; // from __LINE__  const char *file; // from __FILE__  // Could also place a backtrace of void *[16] here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The constructor</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/constructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/constructor/</guid>
      <description>Code domains are 100% constexpr to construct and destruct, as are status codes. This enables the compiler to 100% instantiate both only in its mind, and to emit zero code and thus zero overhead.
Unfortunately it also means that it must be possible for each domain to be instantiated an infinite number of times, and being 100% in constexpr, any instances never have a unique address in memory either. Thus we cannot compare domains for equivalence using their address in memory, as  std::error_category does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String refs</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/string_ref/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/string_ref/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;system_error2&amp;gt; does not use std::string to return possibly statically or dynamically allocated strings, and thus avoids dragging in a lot of the standard library which impacts build times.
Instead status code domains have a string_ref, which has a polymorphic implementation which may or may not manage a dynamic memory allocation using an atomic reference counter. Due to this polymorphism, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry which implementation is actually in use under the bonnet when you pass around string_ref instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redefining `message()`</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/message/</guid>
      <description>You may remember that our custom _file_io_error_domain inherits from outcome_e::posix_code::domain_type, and thus does not have to implement the many pure virtual functions required by outcome_e::status_code_domain.
What we do need to do is reimplement _do_message() to append the file and line information to the POSIX error description string returned by outcome_e::posix_code::domain_type. This causes the status code&amp;rsquo;s .message() observer to return a string with the extra payload information represented in text.
// Return a string describing a specific code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constexpr domain source</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/source/</guid>
      <description>Back in The constructor, we declared but did not implement a .get() function which returns a constexpr static instance of the domain. We implement this now:
// 100% constexpr instantiation constexpr _file_io_error_domain file_io_error_domain; inline constexpr const _file_io_error_domain &amp;amp;_file_io_error_domain::get() { return file_io_error_domain; } View this code on Github As this is 100% constexpr, it can be (and is under optimisation) implemented entirely in the mind of the compiler with no run time representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implicit conversion</title>
      <link>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/implicit_conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ned14.github.io/outcome/experimental/worked-example/implicit_conversion/</guid>
      <description>Back in The payload, we mentioned that there was no default implicit conversion of file_io_error (status_code&amp;lt;_file_io_error_domain&amp;gt;) to error, as error is too small to hold _file_io_error_domain::value_type.
We can tell the framework about available implicit conversions by defining an ADL discovered free function make_status_code() which takes our custom status code as input, and returns an error:
// Now tell `error` how it can implicitly construct from `file_io_error`. // This is done by us defining a free function called `make_status_code()` // which is discovered using ADL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>